utc.com 2019-12-30

# Website and Mobile Privacy Notice | United Technologies

United Technologies Corporation and its subsidiaries and affiliates (collectively, “UTC”) are responsible for this website, including its mobile versions, and we are committed to respecting the privacy of visitors to both. UTC has implemented technical, administrative and physical measures to safeguard any personal information that we may collect.

This Privacy Notice describes our practices related to personal information collected through UTC websites and mobile versions, unless there is a separate privacy notice for the website or mobile version.

UTC has a separate General Privacy Notice that covers personal information that UTC may collect and process separate and apart from its websites and mobile versions. Employees should consult the Employee Privacy Notice. Click here to select the version in the language of your choosing. If you apply for a job through this website, UTC’s use of the personal information you provide through the Careers section is governed by UTC’s Job Applicant Privacy Notice. You can select this notice in the language of your choice from the box below.

##   
Binding Corporate Rules

UTC has adopted Binding Corporate Rules (BCRs) as a mechanism to authorize the sharing of Personal Information between its businesses inside the European Union (EU) and its businesses located in other regions of the world.

## Does this Notice apply to all UTC Websites?

This Privacy Notice applies to visitors of UTC websites that link to this Privacy Notice. Individual websites for UTC entities, services and products may adopt different privacy notices because the transactions taking place on those websites may be different. If a UTC website has its own privacy notice, the provisions of that notice apply to that website.

## What personal information does UTC collect?

UTC monitors user traffic patterns throughout the website according to a user’s domain name, browser type, date and time of access, and pages viewed. This information is collected in order to measure the number of visitors to our website and to determine which areas users find useful based upon the traffic to particular areas. UTC uses this information to enhance visitors’ experience and to better prepare future content based on the interests of visitors.

A visitor to our website may be asked to provide personal information to receive a response or some other service from UTC. The personal information that you may be requested to provide includes your name, email address and any information that you choose to provide. The collection of information will be transparent to you – you will be asked for it and will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to provide it. If you choose not to provide any of the personal information requested, UTC may be unable to complete the transaction you have requested.

Your mobile provider may have a conflicting privacy position that captures personal information when you visit our website, but UTC is not responsible for and does not control how other parties may collect your information when you access our website(s).

## How does UTC use the personal information it collects?

#### Any personal information collected will only be used to:

  * conduct basic business operations, such as communicate with customers and business planning;
  * provide investor services;
  * provide the information, item or service you have requested;
  * communicate with you about products, services and events relating to UTC;
  * improve our products, services and websites;
  * verify your identity to ensure security for one of the other purposes listed here;
  * respond to a legitimate legal request from law enforcement authorities or other government regulators;
  * investigate suspected or actual illegal activity;
  * support the sale or transfer of all or a portion of our business or assets (including through bankruptcy); and/or
  * conduct investigations to ensure compliance with, and comply with, legal obligations.

Information that individuals submit to express interest in, or be considered for, an employment opportunity with UTC is covered by the Applicant Privacy Notice.

Except where used in support of a contract with you or to fulfill a legal obligation, our use of your personal information will be only for legitimate business interests as set forth above.

## Where does UTC store your information?

Because UTC is a global company with locations in many different countries, we may transfer your information from one legal entity to another or from one country to another in order to accomplish the purposes listed above. These countries include, at a minimum, the United States, the many of the member states of the European Union, Canada and other countries, including some in Asia. We will transfer your personal information consistent with applicable legal requirements and only to the extent necessary for the purposes set forth above.

UTC relies on available legal mechanisms to enable the legal transfer of personal information across borders. To the extent that UTC relies on the standard contractual clauses (also called the model clauses) or Binding Corporate Rules to authorize transfer, UTC will comply with those requirements, including where there may be a conflict between those requirements and this Notice. To read UTC’s Binding Corporate Rules, click here to select the version in the language of your choosing.

## Does UTC use your personal information to contact you?

UTC does not use the personal information collected on this website to contact you except in response to a direct inquiry or if you register for communications in the Investors section of this site.

## Does UTC share the information it collects with any third parties?

UTC may share your Personal Information with our subsidiaries and affiliated companies (the “UTC Group”). When UTC transfers your Personal Information within the UTC Group, it will do so consistent with applicable law and UTC’s Binding Corporate Rules, which are available above in many languages.

In addition, UTC may provide access to or share Personal Information on an as-needed basis with third parties, such as trusted service providers, consultants and contractors who are granted access to UTC facilities or systems, and with government agencies and others as required by law. UTC will only share your information outside the UTC Group to:

  * allow service providers UTC has retained to perform services on our behalf. In those cases, UTC will only share the information with service providers for the purposes outlined above. These service providers are contractually restricted from using or disclosing the information except when it is necessary to perform services on our behalf or to comply with legal requirements;
  * comply with legal obligations, including but not limited, to complying with tax and regulatory obligations, sharing data with labor/trade unions and works councils, and responding to a court proceeding or a legitimate legal request from law enforcement authorities or other government regulators;
  * investigate suspected or actual illegal activity;
  * prevent physical harm or financial loss; or
  * support the sale or transfer of all or a portion of our business or assets (including through bankruptcy).

Your personal information may also be maintained and processed by our service providers in countries other than the one in which it was collected, such as the United States, member states of the European Union, Canada and other jurisdictions.

## How long does UTC retain personal information?

UTC will retain personal information as long as needed to comply with its contractual and legal obligations. If the personal information is not subject to contractual or legal obligations, UTC will retain the data for as long as is required for the original purpose for which it was collected.

## How does UTC use cookies or other tracking technologies?

UTC uses cookies on this website. Cookies are small text files sent to and stored on users’ computers that allow websites to recognize repeat users, facilitate users’ access to websites and allow websites to compile aggregate data that will allow content improvements. Cookies do not damage users’ computers or files. If you do not want cookies to be accessible by this or any other UTC website, you should adjust the settings on your browser program to deny or disable the use of cookies. The cookies that UTC uses on this site do not identify you. The cookies simply provide UTC with aggregate, anonymous analytics about the number of people visiting particular pages on this website.

This website may also use web beacons. A web beacon is usually a pixel on a website that can be used to track whether a user has visited a particular website to deliver targeted advertising. Web beacons are used in combination with cookies, which means that, if you turn off your browser’s cookies, the web beacons will not be able to track your activity. The web beacon will still account for a website visit, but your unique information will not be recorded.

United Technologies may also use cookies and similar technology placed by one of our business partners to enable UTC to learn which advertisements bring users to our website. For more information about cookies and other tracking technologies, click [here](http://allaboutcookies.org/).

## What should you understand about the third-party links that may appear on this website?

In some instances, UTC may provide links to non-UTC controlled websites, which UTC will make reasonable efforts to identify as such. UTC does not control such third-party websites, however, and cannot be responsible for the content or the privacy practices employed by other websites.

## What additional information should specific users know?

**Parents, Guardians and Children:** This website is intended for visitors who are at least 18 years of age and the age of majority in their jurisdiction of residence. UTC does not knowingly solicit information from, or market products or services to, children. If you do not meet the age requirements set out above, please do not enter your personal information on this or any other UTC website.

**Users from California:** As defined by California’s “Shine the Light Law,” California residents may annually request and obtain information that is shared with other businesses for their own direct marketing use within the prior calendar year. UTC does not share your personal information with other businesses for their own direct marketing use.

**Users from the European Union and other countries with privacy laws:** You have the right to lodge a complaint with your national or state data protection authority, which may also be known as a supervisory authority. You also have the right to request access to and correction or erasure of your personal information, seek restrictions on or object to the processing of certain personal information, and seek data portability under certain circumstances. To contact UTC about a request to access, correct, erase, object or seek restrictions or portability, please use the contact methods indicated at the end of this notice.

**Users from the United States:** UTC does not collect Social Security Numbers through www.utc.com. UTC does, however, collect Social Security Numbers where required by law, such as tax and payroll purposes for its employees. When UTC collects and/or uses Social Security Numbers, UTC will take proper care by protecting confidentiality, limiting collection, ensuring access on a need-to-know basis, implementing appropriate technical safeguards and ensuring proper disposal.

## How might UTC change this policy?

As UTC expands and improves this website, we may need to update this policy. This policy may be modified from time to time without prior notice. We encourage you to review this policy on a regular basis for any changes. The date of the latest version will be identified at the bottom of the policy.

## How can you contact UTC?

If you have any comments or questions or if there are other things we can do to maximize the value of this website to you, please email [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#61020e0c0c140f08020015080e0f12211415024f020e0c). If you wish to access, correct or update your personal information, or if you have questions about UTC’s privacy practices in general or a complaint, please email [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#95e5e7fce3f4f6ecbbf6faf8e5f9fcf4fbf6f0d5e0e1f6bbf6faf8).

In the event that you are located in a country that will be governed by the General Data Protection Regulation and would like to contact the local Data Protection Officer, please note that in your email and your inquiry will be directed to the appropriate person.

Last updated: November 6, 2019
